Guide to the Nathaniel Terry Bacon Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Nathaniel Terry Bacon papers
1897-1924
MS 696
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.01
Incoming letters of Nathaniel T. Bacon, largely on financial matters from companies in which Bacon had invested. Principal correspondents include Edmund Jandrier about the production methods of the Solvay Process Company, where Bacon worked as technical expert, and his brother Selden.
Bacon, Nathaniel T. (Terry), 1858-1926
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Helen H. Bacon, Mrs. John Westlake, and Mrs. Ronald Ballinger in 1967.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The correspondence is arranged alphabetically.
Related Materials
For additional papers of Nathaniel T. Bacon and information about his family, see the register of the Bacon Family Papers, Manuscript Group No. 46.
Scope and Contents
The Nathaniel Terry Bacon Papers consist of incoming letters, notes, and documents, most of which have to do with the financial affairs of Nathaniel T. Bacon and members of his family. There are small numbers of personal letters from many of his relations, but the principal family correspondent, his brother Selden, wrote mainly about financial matters. There are also many letters from Edmond Jandrier about the production methods of the Solvay Process Company. The other business correspondence of general interest has to do with the affairs of several small companies in which Bacon had invested.
Biographical / Historical
Nathaniel T. Bacon: from 1880-1884 worked for various railroad companies; in 1884 went to Europe to study the Solvay process, and remained connected to that company as technical expert; held executive positions in several other corporations.
Alkali industry and trade; Business; Soda industry; Chemists; Engineers; Bacon, Helen; Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, 1865-1939; Bacon, Nathaniel T. (Terry), 1858-1926; Bacon, Selden, b. 1861; Jandrier, Edmond; Bacon family; Solvay Process Co. (Syracuse, N.Y.)
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  Note: (*) Asterisk indicates ten or more items.
  - Bacon, Alice Mabel, 1912-1916, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bacon, Benjamin Wisner (1860-), 1916-1923 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bacon, David (1895-), 1916-1923, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bacon, Helen (Hazard) (*), 1916-1924 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bacon, Henry Selden, 1907, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bacon, Josephine (Daskam), 1903-1918 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey (1865-1939) (*), 1917-1924 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bacon, Letitia Jordan, 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bacon, Selden (1861-) (*), 1901-1906 (Box 1, Folder 9 - 12)
  - Bacon, Selden (*), 1907 March-1908 December (Box 1, Folder 13 - 17)
  - Bacon, Selden (*), 1916-1925 (Box 1, Folder 18 - 19)
  - Bacon, Susan Almira (1869-1946) (*), 1916-1918, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bacon, Theodore Davenport (1863-), 1916-1920 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bacon family (miscellaneous) (*), 1912-1924, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - By-Products Syndicate (*), 1903-1906 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Colombia Company (*), 1903-1907 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Connecticut Mutual Life Insurance Co., 1898-1904 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Corwin, Magaret Wardell (Bacon) (1866-), 1916-1920 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Exposed Treasure Mining Company (*), 1904 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Fisher, Irving, 1917, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Free-Piston Gas Engine Co. (*), 1903-1906 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Fyffe, Joseph, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Fyffe, Katherine (Bacon), estate of (*), 1911-1924 (Box 2, Folder 31 - 33)
  - Gayley, Charles Mills (1858-1932), 1912 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Greene, Elizabeth Rogers (Bacon) (1881-) (*), 1915-1924 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Hazard, Caroline, 1921-1924, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Jandrier, Edmond (*), 1897-1919 (Box 2, Folder 37 - 39)
  - Keith, Elmer (*), 1917-1923 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Keith, Susan (Bacon) (1889-) (*), 1913-1923 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Point Judith Oyster Company (*), 1906, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Rhode Island Hospital Trust Company, 1901-1903 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Ripley, Mabel Ginevra (Bacon), 1916-1917 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Solvay Process Company (*), 1895-1909 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Southern Realty Company, 1904-1905 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Split Rock Cable Road Company (*), 1897-1906 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Tully Pipe Line Company (*), 1897-1906 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Wildman & Gray (attorneys) (*), 1901-1902 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Wildman & Gray (*), 1903-1908 (Box 3, Folder 50 - 52)
  - Woolsey, John, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Woolsey, Theodore S. (1852-1929), 1912 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Unidentified and miscellaneous (*), 1903-1922 (Box 3, Folder 55)